math_topics = {
    "Number and Algebra": {
        "Numbers and their operations": [["laws of indices", "finding highest common factor (HCF) and lowest common multiple (LCM)","approximation and estimation"],
                                         [{"question_data":{"optionA":"x^4",
                                                        "optionB":"x^3",
                                                        "optionC":"x^8",
                                                        "rightOption":"optionA",
                                                        "question":"Simplify the expression (x^6)/(x^2) using the law of indices."}
                                                        },
                                        {"question_data":{"optionA":"a^(-2) * b^5",
                                                        "optionB":"a^2 * b^5",
                                                        "optionC":"a^(-2) * b^(-5)",
                                                        "rightOption":"optionB",
                                                        "question":"Evaluate the expression (a^(-3) * b^2) / (a^(-1) * b^(-3)) using the law of indices."}
                                                        },
                                        {"question_data":{"optionA":"2^2",
                                                        "optionB":"2^4",
                                                        "optionC":"2^5",
                                                        "rightOption":"optionB",
                                                        "question":"Simplify the expression (2^3)^2 * 2^(-4) using the law of indices."}
                                                        },]
                                        ],
        "Ratio and proportion": [["direct and inverse proportion", "map scales (distance and area)",],
                                [{"question_data":{"optionA":"10",
                                                "optionB":"20",
                                                "optionC":"40",
                                                "rightOption":"optionC",
                                                "question":"If y is directly proportional to x and y = 20 when x = 5, what is the value of y when x = 10?"}
                                                },
                                {"question_data":{"optionA":"2 hours",
                                                "optionB":"3 hours",
                                                "optionC":"4.8 hours",
                                                "rightOption":"optionB",
                                                "question":"If the time taken to travel a certain distance is inversely proportional to the speed of travel, and it takes 4 hours to travel the distance at 60 km/h, how long will it take to travel the same distance at 80 km/h?"}
                                                },
                                {"question_data":{"optionA":"312.5 grams",
                                                "optionB":"525 grams",
                                                "optionC":"625 grams",
                                                "rightOption":"optionC",
                                                "question":"A recipe for a cake requires 250 grams of flour to serve 4 people. How much flour is needed to serve 10 people, assuming the amount of flour is directly proportional to the number of servings?"}
                                                },]],

        "Percentage": [["increasing and decreasing a quantity by a given percentage ", "expressing one quantity as a percentage of another", ],
                    
                        [  {"question_data": {"optionA": "$600",
                                            "optionB": "$650",
                                            "optionC": "$700",
                                            "optionD": "$750",
                                            "rightOption": "optionA",
                                            "question": "A laptop is originally priced at $800. During a sale, its price is decreased by 25%. What is the new price of the laptop?"
                                            }
                            },
                            { "question_data": {"optionA": "40%",
                                                "optionB": "50%",
                                                "optionC": "60%",
                                                "optionD": "70%",
                                                "rightOption": "optionC",
                                                "question": "If a class has 20 boys and 30 girls, what percentage of the class is girls?"
                                                }
                            }
                        ]
                    ],
        # ... other subtopics ...
    },
    "Geometry and Measurement": {
        "Coordinate geometry": [["finding the gradient of a straight line", "finding the length of a line segment",],
                                [{"question_data": {
                                "optionA": "1/2",
                                "optionB": "2",
                                "optionC": "-1/2",
                                "rightOption": "optionB",
                                "question": "What is the gradient of the straight line that passes through the points (2, 3) and (4, 7)?"
                                            },
                                },
                                {
                                "question_data": {
                                    "optionA": "5 units",
                                    "optionB": "10 units",
                                    "optionC": "8.2 units",
                                    "rightOption": "optionC",
                                    "question": "What is the length of the line segment between the points (1, 2) and (7, 6)?"
                                }
                                }
                                ]],


        "Vectors in two dimensions": [["vector notations", "representing a vector as a line segment","magnitude of vector",],
                                      [{"question_data": {"optionA": "5 units",
                                                        "optionB": "10 units",
                                                        "optionC": "âˆš29 units",
                                                        "rightOption": "optionC",
                                                        "question": "What is the magnitude of the vector represented by the coordinates (3, 5)?"
                                                    }
                                                    }  
                                      ]],
        "Pythagoras' theorem": [["use of trigonometric ratios", "sine rule and cosine rule","area of triangle with sin"],
                                [{"question_data": {"optionA": "24 square units",
                                                    "optionB": "30 square units",
                                                    "optionC": "36 square units",                                                    
                                                    "rightOption": "optionB",
                                                    "question": "What is the area of a triangle with sides of lengths 5, 12, and 13 units?"
                                                }
                                                }
                                ]],
        "Properties of circles": [["symmetry properties of circles ", "angle properties of circles",],
                                  [{"question_data": {"optionA": "True",
                                                    "optionB": "False",
                                                    "optionC": "Depends on the radius of the circle",
                                                    "rightOption": "optionA",
                                                    "question": "Is the angle at the center of a circle always twice the angle at the circumference subtended by the same arc?"
                                                }
                                        }
                                        ]],
        "Congruence and similarity": [["congruent figures and similar figures ", "ratio of volumes of similar solids",],
                                      [{"question_data": {"optionA": "2:1",
                                                        "optionB": "4:1",
                                                        "optionC": "8:1",
                                                        "optionD": "16:1",
                                                        "rightOption": "optionC",
                                                        "question": "If two similar solids have a linear scale factor of 2, what is the ratio of their volumes?"
                                                    }
                                                    }
                                    ]],


        # ... other subtopics ...
    },
    # "Statistics and Probability": {
    #     "Data Representation": [["Requirement 1", "Requirement 2", ]],
    #     "Probability Concepts": [["Requirement 1", "Requirement 2", ]],a
    #     # ... other subtopics ...
    # }
    # # ... other topics ...
}
        

